WOMAN : It scares us just thinking about it .
When you hear it , you 're gonna think we 're insane .
It started out small ...
like a hand or a leg was in a different position .
And then its head was looking up instead of down ...
and then one day , it was in a completely different room .
It was moving around by itself .
Camilla got in touch with a medium . We learned from her ...
that the doll was possessed by a girl named Annabelle Higgins .
She had lost her parents and had taken a liking to my doll .
All she wanted was to be friends .
When we heard this , we felt really sorry for her . I mean ,
we 're nurses , we help people .
But then things got worse .
MAN 1 : How did you end up with it ?
WOMAN : It was a gift from my mom , for my birthday .
I don 't know where she got it ...
but we are beyond terrified .
[ INDISTINCT WHISPERING ]
FATHER PEREZ : God honors sacrifice .
And our sacrifices touch God 's heart and move his hand .
Jesus said , " This is my commandment .
That you love one another as I have loved you .
Greater love hath no one than this ...
that he lay down his life for his friends . "
JOHN : I win .
FATHER PEREZ : Let us pray .
Good to see you too . We 'll see you soon .
Hey , you .
Oh .
Okay , so , uh ...
who won ?
John . But he cheats .
What ? It was two against one . I had to do something , right ?
Yeah , right .
JOHN : What ?
Where did Sharon get off to ?
- Oh , I 'll find her . - Thanks .
Bye .
Pete send you after me ?
I swear , one day he thinks I 'll just ...
run off too .
[ CHUCKLES ]
Men .
What would they do without us ? I mean , honestly .
- JOHN : Hey , wait a second . Let me help you out . - MIA : Heh .
- We appreciate the lift , Pete . - PETE : Sure thing .
You just make sure to take care of this wife and baby of yours .
Did we ask about names yet ?
- Sharon . - What ? It 's not prying .
- I don 't know her . - It 's just conversation .
- We 're still working on them anyway . - But we 're pretty sure " John " if it 's a boy .
- And we 're thinking " Phyllis " if it 's a girl . - Heh . We were ?
- Yeah . You said you liked it . - Heh . I never said that .
- It 's my grandmother 's name . - And I can 't stand your grandmother .
PETE : Oh , dear .
I mean , it 's not only me . Nobody can stand her .
- No , she 's right , everyone hates her . - PETE : Ha-ha-ha .
Okay , well , on that note ...
Sharon , let 's go inside . These two , they have a lot to talk about .
- SHARON : Mm . - Thank you again .
SHARON : Think nothing of it .
Just remember :
Children are a blessing .
Indeed they are .
And then they learn to talk .
- MIA : Heh . - Oh , you .
Bye .
I guess that 's a " no " on Phyllis ?
[ MIA CHUCKLES ]
We shouldn 't talk about the baby so much in front of them .
- I just think it isn 't right . - Why not ?
Well , they only lost their daughter two years ago .
They didn 't lose their daughter , Mia .
She ran away and joined up with the hippies .
By now she 's probably got three husbands and calls herself " Star . "
Well , even " Star " is a better name than Phyllis .
Oh , you didn 't lock it ?
No . Why would I ?
You have to start locking it , John . I mean , it 's a different world now .
MAN [ ON TV ] : They call themselves " The Family . "
But police officials have labeled them a dangerous cult .
Residing on the grounds of Spahn Ranch ...
once used as the backdrop for many well-known Westerns ...
the Family is estimated to have close to 30 members ...
many of them with histories of heavy drug use and criminal behavior .
Currently , several Family members are in custody ...
awaiting charges for the brutal Tate and LaBianca murders ...
which held Los Angeles in the grip of fear ...
before police investigators were led to the suspects ...
Hey , honey ?
Do you think you could shut off the TV ? It 's making it a little hard to concentrate .
MAN [ ON TV ] : Their leader , Charles Manson , was sometimes referred to ...
as both " God " and " Satan " by his devoted followers ...
and had predicted an Armageddon-like event he called Helter Skelter .
Thank you .
Hey . You know what , you shouldn 't even be watching that stuff . All right ?
It could upset the baby . There 's new research out there ...
- Oh , boy , more new research ? - It 's true .
They are learning that babies in utero ...
experience more of the outside world than they ever thought possible .
They recognize voices and noises , songs .
You know , I bet the men that did that research spent millions of dollars ...
when they could have just asked the mother for free .
How 's it going in here ?
Um ...
Well ...
I am trying my hardest to enjoy it .
Everyone keeps telling me that ...
once you 're in the residency it gets a million times worse .
I haven 't even mentioned the fact that I 'm about to be a new father .
Why not ?
I don 't know .
Sometimes you just don 't wanna hear how difficult it 's gonna be .
" Difficult " ?
No , maybe difficult 's not the right word .
Uh , challenging ?
Are you talking about the residency , or me and the baby ?
I don 't know .
All of it , I guess .
I mean , it 's not like this is an ideal situation for what I 'm about to go through .
Like what we 're about to go through .
I didn 't mean for that to sound like it did . I 'm sorry .
It 's not like difficult or challenging are bad things , anyway .
Look , I know that I 've been a little caught up in my own world lately .
- Some people might call it self-centered . - " Some people " ?
Most people ?
Everyone ?
Can we just go back and redo the last two minutes , please ?
Please ?
It 's fine .
I know you 're stressed .
I 'm just a little , uh , oversensitive lately .
Yeah .
- Do you want me to tell you why ? - Yes , doctor .
- Okay , well , good . So ... - Heh .
In my , um , almost expert opinion ...
you are a little sensitive ...
because you are a lot pregnant .
Honey , I 'm sorry , Mia . I am .
Yes . I 'm stressed about finishing med school ...
and I 'm freaking out about matching ...
but I 've never been happier .
Ever .
Okay ? And that 's because of you .
And it .
Oh , you know what ?
There 's something I wanna give you .
Oh , no . The last time you said that I ended up pregnant .
JOHN : Yes , you did .
[ LULLABY PLAYING OVER MOBILE SPEAKER ]
JOHN : Okay , close your eyes .
All right . Hold on a second . I was waiting on this until the baby , but ...
You were feeling a little ...
Guilty , yes . Because of what I said .
Okay . Open your eyes .
You didn 't .
[ JOHN GRUNTS ]
Oh , my God , John .
- That 's the one , right ? - MIA : Yes .
Where did you find her ? I mean , do you know how long I 've been looking ?
- I know . - Heh .
I 'd completely lost hope .
Well , I have my ways .
[ MIA CHUCKLES ]
We 'll be a little short on the rent the next few months , but , uh ...
MIA : There . She fits right in .
JOHN : That completes the set , right ?
Yes , it does .
Thank you . I love her .
[ WOMAN SCREAMS ]
John ?
John , wake up .
- What is it ? Is it the baby ? - No , no .
Next door , I heard a scream .
I think something 's wrong .
Stay here . I 'll go check it out .
John , wait !
Shouldn 't we call the cops ?
Because you think you heard a scream ?
No , just let me go check it out . They 'd do the same for us .
If they heard me scream , I 'd rather they call the cops .
Think they heard you scream .
- Just be careful . - I will .
John ?
- Oh , my God ! You 're covered in blood . - It 's not mine .
Go back inside and call an ambulance , right now . Go !
WOMAN [ OVER PHONE ] : 911 operator .
I need an ambulance .
WOMAN : What 's your location ?
307 Gardner Road .
WOMAN : In Santa Monica ?
Yeah .
WOMAN : What 's your emergency ?
I don 't know , but ...
[ PANTING ]
There 's a lot of blood .
Please , just be as fast as possible .
WOMAN : I like your dolls .
My husband 's coming back .
Just take whatever you want and just get out !
[ MIA GASPS THEN SCREAMS ]
JOHN : Mia !
[ GRUNTING ]
Get out of here !
Get out ! Get out of here , Mia !
[ WOMAN SCREAMS ]
[ ALL SHOUTING AND SCREAMING ]
[ JOHN GRUNTS ]
[ BANGING ON DOOR ]
POLICEMAN : Open up !
- Open the door ! - I got you .
- Open up , this is the police . - I got you .
Open the door !
JOHN : You just breathe .
You 're all right . We got you .
I 'm right here . I 'm right here with you .
MAN [ ON TV ] : In a tragic scene described by one investigator ...
as reminiscent of a horrific occult ritual ...
a man and his wife were brutally stabbed to death ...
by their estranged daughter , Annabelle Higgins , and her unidentified boyfriend .
The two are believed to be members of a cult .
The male suspect was shot and killed as police arrived on scene ...
while the daughter was found in an apparent suicide , her throat slit open .
One officer summed up these blood-soaked murders by saying :
" In all my years , I have never seen anything quite as gruesome as this . "
[ HEART BEATING ]
DOCTOR : And while the amniotic sac wasn 't punctured ...
and isn 't ruptured ...
we are seeing signs of strain on the cervix .
Most likely caused by the trauma .
Which is why ...
I am putting you on bed rest for the remainder of your pregnancy .
Now , you can get up and use the facilities ...
if you do so delicately .
But anything beyond that would be putting you and your child at risk . All right ?
- Yes , sir . Thank you . - DOCTOR : Okay .
The lock .
I had them scrub everything . At least twice .
Now you could perform surgery in there , it 's so clean .
You didn 't have to do that .
You 're on bed rest for a while . You 'd go crazy if I didn 't .
Just don 't get all obsessed with those daytime soaps .
You know I can 't stand them .
I 'll bring your sewing bag in later on .
Okay ? We can turn the whole room into your own little sweatshop .
What is it ?
You think the baby 's okay ?
JOHN : The baby is not even aware of what happened .
MIA : Oh , really ? Because I heard there 's some new research that , um , you know ...
Mia , come on .
You heard the doctors .
So if you listen to them , the baby is fine .
The baby is fine .
I mean , you 're its mother , right ?
If it wasn 't , you would know .
But if something does happen ...
What ? What 's gonna happen ?
Like when I go into labor , John .
Mia .
You 'll save the baby over me .
- Come on . - We have to talk about it .
I mean , I can 't have anything ever happen to it .
You promise me .
You promise me you 'll save the baby .
Yeah , Mia , I promise .
But you know what ?
It 's gonna be okay .
You are gonna be fine .
[ CLOCK TICKING ]
[ LULLABY PLAYING OVER MOBILE SPEAKERS ]
[ SEWING MACHINE RATTLING ]
What the hell is that ?
- John ? - Shh , shh , shh .
- John ? - It 's okay .
[ ROCKING CHAIR CREAKING ]
PHIL [ ON TV ] : I 'm your friend , you know that , don 't you ?
Are you , Phil ?
PHIL : Of course I am .
Well , then , I have a friend .
You have been terribly nice this past week . Going to the movie ...
Out to dinner . Even dancing .
It 's been a lot of fun for me .
[ ROCKING CHAIR CREAKING ]
[ CREAKING STOPS ]
- JOHN : How 'd it go today ? - MIA : Uh ...
- TV went out again . - Really ?
Must be that room . That never did that in the den .
What is all that ?
Uh , this is a bunch of random stuff that I picked up at the store ...
to satisfy any pregnancy cravings .
You know , it 's funny , I haven 't really had any cravings . It 's funny .
[ MIA GASPS ]
Pickles .
Oh , my God , you know what would go really well with pickles ?
[ MIA CHUCKLES ]
John Form , we are meant to be together .
Yeah , I know .
- Like , uh , mustard and pickles . - Heh-heh-heh .
- Heh . - Mm .
Did you get to have your meeting today ?
Yeah , I did .
He , uh , thinks I 've got a real shot at Huntington Memorial .
Of course you do .
It 's in Pasadena , though . It 's a little further from the beach . You okay with that ?
Mm .
Change of view would be good .
Yeah .
There 's this one day conference in Sacramento that he thinks I should attend ...
that , uh , could help move things in that direction .
I fly out for a day in a few days .
It 's only a couple days .
I 'll be fine .
Yeah , we gotta get you back to bed .
You shouldn 't be sitting up this long .
Let 's go .
Oh , and , uh , Detective Clarkin called today .
He said he wanted to stop by at some point this week .
I 've already told him everything . I 'd rather just forget the whole thing .
I know . He just said he wanted to go over a few things .
That doll .
We have to get rid of it . I mean , she had it in her hands .
No , you 're right . You 're right . Just , um , consider it gone .
MIA : I suppose you can tell Detective Clarkin he can stop by whenever it 's convenient .
I mean , it 's not like I 'm going anywhere anytime soon .
CLARKIN : They were members of a cult .
We 've confirmed that it was Higgins' daughter and her boyfriend .
- You may have heard on the news ... - That cults are taking over the world ?
Well , it 's not quite as prevalent as they 'd have you believe .
You 're gonna have a hard time convincing us of that .
Were they satanic ?
It 's okay . She should know .
Yes .
Yes , it is believed that they had interest in the occult .
That they did this to prove their devotion ...
a sort of violence for violence 's sake .
But that 's crazy .
Well , crazy people do crazy things , ma 'am .
But that 's all this was .
I 'll tell you what .
I 'll dig a little deeper .
See what I can find .
And if I come up with anything further , I 'll reach out and I 'll let you ...
No , no .
Thank you .
But , um , unless it has something to do with our safety ...
I 'd rather not hear any more about it .
Okay .
I understand .
Okay . Good .
Right there .
Thank you .
I 'm making popcorn .
- MAN 1 [ ON TV ] : Tim Conway 's here . - MAN 2 [ ON TV ] : And John Wayne .
MAN 1 : He backed out again ? !
[ AUDIENCE LAUGHING ON TV ]
JOHN : Are you sure it 's okay for the baby to have this much butter and s ...
- MAN 2 : Raquel Welch and Sophia Loren . - MAN 1 : Now , you know they 're not here .
- MAN 2 : Well , where are they ? - MAN 1 : I don 't know where they are .
MAN 2 : Let 's get them on !
- MIA : How you feeling ? - JOHN : A little nervous .
They are gonna love you .
I love you .
I love you too .
I realize , Miss Prentice , but you still have time . Mind if I look around ?
But wouldn 't you be more comfortable sitting down ?
[ POPPING ]
MAN [ ON TV ] : I do know how painful this must be for you .
Look , it had absolutely nothing to do with the money !
Look , I don 't even want to talk about it . I don 't wanna think about it . I ...
Why don 't you just leave now .
What if they 're not dead ? What 'll you do then ?
I told you , I don 't know ! Would you please leave ? !
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GASPS ]
MIA : Help me !
[ COUGHS ]
[ GASPS THEN GROANS ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ BANGING ON DOOR ]
POLICEMAN : I got you . I got you . It 's okay . Come here .
Excuse me .
Hey . Hey .
Hi .
I 'm so sorry that I wasn 't here . I am so sorry .
Behind you .
Congratulations .
- It 's a girl . - This is my baby .
Oh , my gosh .
[ CHUCKLES ]
Leah ?
Leah . Hi .
Hi , Leah , it 's your daddy .
Look at her .
Hi .
- John ... - Yeah ?
- John , the fire ... - Oh , shh .
It 's fine . She 's fine . You 're fine .
No .
I don 't know what happened .
It 's like the house is accursed .
I can never go back there . I can 't . I can 't , not with her . No .
You don 't have to .
Ever .
[ LEAH CRYING ]
Come on , come on .
[ MIA SHUSHING ]
[ FOOTSTEPS THUDDING ]
Hey , honey , you all set ?
Any second now ...
she is gonna ...
[ MUFFLED FOOTSTEPS ]
And then ...
[ THUDDING THEN MIA CHUCKLES ]
You need to get out more . Come on , we 'll be late .
You really think we should go ? I mean , Leah 's being a little fussy .
Mia , she 's fine . Okay ? You both need to get out of here .
- You 've been cooped up in here too much . - I know , but it 's ...
Look at it out here .
It 's beautiful .
Okay ? Come on , you need this . I need this . Leah , she could definitely use some color .
Heh . Stop it ! She 's perfect .
Maybe we could put some of that , uh , what do you call it , what do you use these ... ?
Oh , cocoa butter . Maybe we should slather her with some cocoa butter .
Okay , okay .
I will go as long as you stop talking .
Mm . I promise .
- Let 's go . - Come on .
We 're going .
[ LEAH WHIMPERING ]
FATHER PEREZ : We cannot let fear control us .
For we are never truly alone ...
when we walk with God .
Isn 't it true that the more we know about something the less fear we have from it ?
We need to face our fears to better understand them .
We need to shine a bright light ...
on the monsters that feed on our insecurities ...
on our anxieties ...
and on the doubt we cast on ourselves .
We need to remember that , for those who have faith ...
this light of truth is everlasting .
Mia . Mind if I take a picture of your little one ?
I like to hang photos of the newest members of the congregation
- on the visitors ' bulletin board . - Ah , yes . Sure , of course .
No , no , no . Hold her on your lap .
Oh , you don 't need me in the photo .
Of course I do .
Mothers are closer to God than any other living creature .
For only they can share in God 's creative miracle .
Leah .
[ FATHER PEREZ SPEAKING IN SPANISH ]
Ah ! Leah ! Heh .
Wonderful .
That should do it .
I still feel the Higgins' absence every Sunday .
- I imagine it must be difficult for you ... - Oh , there 's John . I should go .
We still have a lot of boxes to unpack .
Well , unfortunately , I don 't have a prayer to help you with that .
Well , I guess there are some things we need to take care of ourselves .
Yes . Goodbye .
Father Perez .
[ DOLL LAUGHING ]
I think this is the last of them .
Somebody pop the champagne .
[ BOTH CHUCKLING ]
[ LEAH CRYING ]
JOHN : I 'll get her .
[ CLICKING TONGUE ]
[ LULLABY PLAYING OVER MOBILE SPEAKERS ]
[ MIA SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
Wait a sec , how did that get in there ? I swear I threw it out .
I don 't know .
Things must have gotten mixed up after the fire .
Here , give her to me .
No .
You gave her to me as a gift .
Like Father Perez said , we should celebrate our strength , right ?
You sure ?
Yeah .
[ MIA SIGHS ]
There . She fits right in .
Come to Mommy ! Come to Mommy !
[ MIA SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
[ LEAH GIGGLES ]
MAN [ ON TV ] : General Hospital :
Where doctors and nurses dedicate their lives ...
to that wonder which is a human being .
[ LEAH CRYING ]
MAN [ ON TV ] : ... an ever-changing challenge of love and hope , loneliness and despair .
General Hospital on ABC .
Doctors and nurses with first names and last names , and tragedies of their own .
- Oh , I 'm so sorry . - MIA : Excuse me .
Oh , sorry . Thank you .
Hi !
Do you live here too ?
- We live ups ... - Don 't tell her .
We 're not supposed to tell . She 's a stranger .
That 's a very good rule to have .
I like your doll .
I have one just like it .
You do ?
A few , actually .
I 'm Mia and this is Leah .
[ LEAH SQUEALS ]
Yeah .
What 's your name ?
- It 's Nan ... - I said , don 't tell her .
[ GIRL SIGHS ]
Well , maybe one day , we can all be friends .
Hey . You 're the new tenants at the Palmeri , aren 't you ?
Yes .
I suppose this little one is pretty much new to everything .
MIA : This is Leah .
WOMAN : She 's adorable .
I 'm Mia .
Evelyn , hi .
Here . This was my daughter 's favorite .
Maybe Leah will like it too , when she 's a little older .
That 's very sweet . Thank you .
Well , feel free to stop by anytime .
Thank you .
MIA : Hey .
Look what they drew for you .
See ! That 's us .
We 're making friends already .
Yeah .
At least we 're getting a little exercise .
Look at this .
Should we , uh , talk to their parents ?
If Leah did something like this , I would want to know about it .
Leah would never do anything like this . This isn 't even good .
- Look at the proportions . - Ugh , John .
JOHN : Yes , Mia , if she did , I would want to know too .
Okay , so let 's go find out where they live , introduce ourselves .
But let 's not make a big deal out of this , okay ?
It 's not like this is a threat or anything . This is just ...
- one kid with an overactive imagination . - I know . I know , I know .
JOHN : You gotta remember that we moved here to get away from what happened .
We packed up our clothes , we packed up our furniture . We packed up the good memories .
But the fears and the anxieties , we promised to leave those behind .
MIA : It is not as easy as it sounds , John .
You 're off at work , having adult conversation , and I 'm here ...
JOHN : Working yourself up over nothing .
Look , I 'm sorry . Look , okay , you know what ?
Tomorrow night , I don 't have to work late .
Okay , so I say I come home , we sit down ...
we have a nice dinner ...
and we have some adult conversation .
Okay ? Can we do that ?
[ THE ASSOCIATION 'S " CHERISH " PLAYING ON PHONOGRAPH ]
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
[ INDISTINCT WHISPERING ]
[ MIA SCREAMS ]
[ GROANS ]
[ GIRL GIGGLING ]
MIA : Hello ?
[ SEWING MACHINE RATTLING ]
Who are you ?
[ WIND BLOWING ]
[ YELLING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
JOHN : There isn 't anyone here .
It 's just you , me and Leah .
- MIA : I know what I saw . It was her . - JOHN : Mia ...
There are things happening that I can 't explain , John .
What things ?
Baby , are you sure they 're not just manifestations of your anxiety ?
It 's perfectly normal for new mothers to experience postpartum ...
You know that being a doctor doesn 't make you an expert on everything , right ?
[ CEILING RUMBLING , THEN FOOTSTEPS THUDDING ]
I think we should talk to someone .
Like who ?
A shrink ?
I 'm not crazy , John . I 'm not crazy , John .
I 'm not saying that you 're crazy , okay . And I 'm not talking about a shrink .
JOHN : So we turned to the Church , Father .
It 's what my parents did when they hit a rough patch ...
and it worked for them .
I understand , of course .
But you two hit more than just a rough patch .
In a matter of months , you 've experienced the very worst of life .
And the very best .
A pendulum swing like that is enough to shake even the strongest foundations .
But you survived .
And instead of trying to forget this bad history ...
I think you should use it as an example of how strong you two can be when united .
You don 't come out the other side of something like this weaker .
You come out stronger .
You 're right .
Good .
- Hey ! - Oh , hi .
- Mia , right ? - Yes .
And , of course , I remember Leah . You are ... ?
- Hi . John . - Hi .
This is Evelyn . She owns the bookstore I was telling you about .
- Right . Yeah . Thank you for the book . - I couldn 't help myself .
I saw your girls and I felt like I had known them a long time .
So where is this beautiful family off to ?
- We 're just seeing him out . - I have to get to the hospital .
- They put me on the night shift . - I think he did something terrible .
They say that I 'm being rewarded .
Well , if you guys ever want a tour of the neighborhood , don 't hesitate to call me .
Thank you .
- Blessed day . - Bye .
I should probably go too . Go to Mommy ?
Come on !
[ RADIO SHOW THEME SONG PLAYING ON RADIO ]
[ DOOR CREAKING THEN THUDDING ]
[ THE SPIRAL STAIRCASE 'S " MORE TODAY THAN YESTERDAY " PLAYING ON TV ]
[ MIA SHUSHING ]
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
[ ELEVATOR BELL DINGS ]
[ BABY CRYING ]
[ TIRES SQUEAKING ]
[ BABY WAILING ]
[ WAILING STOPS ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ PANTING ]
[ ELEVATOR BELL DINGS ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
Come on ! Come on !
[ ELEVATOR RUMBLING AND WHIRRING ]
[ ELEVATOR BELL DINGS ]
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
[ MIA GRUNTS ]
[ LEAH CRYING ]
MIA : Leah !
[ MIA SCREAMS ]
Leah !
[ TINKLING AND RATTLING ]
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
Help me !
[ GROWLING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ MIA WHIMPERING ]
[ ROARING THEN MIA SCREAMS ]
[ PANTING ]
[ FOOTSTEPS THUDDING ]
MIA : Oh , heh .
I 'm sorry .
Thank you .
Thank you for meeting with me .
It 's fine .
I was a little surprised to hear from you , though . Last time we spoke ...
I said I didn 't want to know any more .
Having had a little distance I am ...
Well , I realized I could use some closure .
I mean , there 're just too many unanswered questions .
I understand .
I brought what I have on the Higgins case .
That 's Annabelle there . The Higgins girl .
That was , clearly , taken before she got caught up in the cult .
Looks a lot different than the last time you saw her , doesn 't she ?
This cult that she was in ...
did you look further into it ?
For what , specifically ?
I don 't know , there must have been some motive for their attacks .
- Crazy people do crazy things . - Crazy things . I know .
They didn 't think they were crazy .
They had to have had a reason .
After a little more digging , I did find that their act wasn 't devotional .
That they were actually trying to conjure something up .
Like what ?
The Devil ? Demons ?
The Tooth Fairy . I don 't know specifically .
- It doesn 't really matter anywa ... - Why not ?
Well , because this is all just a bunch of hocus-pocus .
Um ...
Please .
CLARKIN : Ma 'am ...
these were miscreants .
They were probably hopped up on God knows what ...
and it made them see and do all sorts of ...
terrible things .
Does this mean anything to you ?
Have you ever heard the expression :
" Sometimes a cigar is just a cigar " ?
Then you won 't mind if I , uh , keep this one for myself .
Um ...
And one more thing . Does the cult have a name ?
They called themselves " The Disciples of the Ram . "
Hello again .
Is there anything I can help you with ?
Oh , no , no , no . I was just browsing , really .
I just learned something .
You 're a terrible liar .
Now , what is it you 're looking for ?
- Maybe I 'll come back . - Mia .
I 'm old .
Which means there 's very little that surprises me anymore .
And if it does , I 'm too tired to show it .
Now , you gonna tell me ? Or we just ...
I think my family 's being haunted by a ghost .
Aisle four . Follow me .
I know it sounds crazy , the ghost of this girl haunting us , but I just ...
No crazier than the Red Sea parting .
To nonbelievers , it 's all crazy .
So you believe in this stuff ?
Let 's just say that I 've had one or two experiences in my life ...
that have helped me to keep an open mind .
I don 't particularly think what you 're experiencing is the ghost of that girl .
Why not ?
Well , ghosts haunt specific places .
Usually where something terrible has happened .
Like your old house .
But we moved and it 's still happening .
Which is why I don 't think it 's a ghost .
But now , that cult ?
You said that they were trying to summon something .
From what I 've read in the past ...
these cults , they don 't summon ghosts .
They summon inhuman spirits .
Something that 's never existed in the flesh .
Demons .
What do they want ?
A soul .
And they won 't stop until they get one .
What do I do ?
Hopefully , the answer is in one of these books .
My daughter , Ruby .
She passed away when she was about your age .
I 'm sorry .
Without her , I felt like I had nothing else to live for , so ...
But as I lay there , waiting for it all to end ...
I heard her voice .
She told me that it wasn 't my time .
That God had another purpose for me .
You , too , have a purpose , Mia .
To protect your family .
So don 't think you 're crazy for trying to do that .
You do what you think is right .
You do what you have to do .
[ LEAH BABBLING ]
WOMAN : Mia .
[ TRUCK HORN HONKING ]
[ LEAH WHIMPERING ]
MIA : " The Devil preys on the weak and the vulnerable .
[ LEAH WHIMPERS ]
Seeking to devour their souls ...
To perform incantations ...
Spilling the blood of kin .
Spilling the blood of an innocent . "
But how do I stop it ?
[ LEAH BABBLES ]
Hey .
[ ROCKING CHAIR CREAKING ]
[ LULLABY MUSIC PLAYING OVER MOBILE SPEAKER ]
[ CREAKING STOPS ]
[ FURNITURE THUDDING ]
[ MIA WHIMPERING ]
MIA : Leah .
[ FLOOR CREAKING ]
Leah !
[ GRUNTS ]
[ LEAH CRYING ]
[ LEAH WAILING ]
[ MIA SHUSHING ]
[ FLOOR CREAKING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
MIA : Oh , my God !
[ MIA SCREAMING ]
[ LEAH WAILING ]
What happened ?
Help us . You gotta help us , John .
- Thank you for coming , Father . - Sure , of course .
I 'll take your coat .
Mia ...
this doll ...
may I see it ?
- MIA : John got rid of her . - JOHN : Or tried to .
MIA : There she was , at the bottom of one of our last boxes .
JOHN : I still don 't understand what the doll has to do with this supposed demon .
Demons can sometimes use objects as conduits to achieve their desired goal .
" Their desired goal " ?
Our souls , John .
That 's why it 's after Leah .
- It wants her soul . - FATHER PEREZ : No , no , no .
Demons can 't just take souls , Mia .
A soul needs to be offered to the demon before it can take it .
Well , I don 't plan on offering my soul anytime soon .
The Devil is the father of lies .
Demons are his manipulators .
No one ever plans to offer their soul .
How do we get rid of it ?
- How do we stop it from coming back ? - FATHER PEREZ : I don 't know .
Not yet .
But someone at the church might .
At the very least , I 've heard of a married couple ...
that the church has worked with in the past that deal with this type of thing .
They 're back East , but a call can always be placed .
What do we do in the meantime ?
I can 't have Leah anywhere near that doll .
Let me take her .
Perhaps , if she 's stored in a sacred place ...
it will weaken the demon enough , it won 't have the strength to return .
Thank you , Father .
Of course .
JOHN : Come on , let 's get you to bed . Doctor 's orders .
Oh , no . No , John . I can 't . Not until I know it 's not coming back .
Mia . Come on , what if ...
- What if I ... - John , I can 't .
What if I just stayed up with her ?
You get some rest .
- All right ? - Okay .
Good night .
John .
Yeah ?
Thank you for believing me .
I didn 't know if you would .
Mia , come on .
I love you .
I will always believe you .
Good night .
You think Father Perez can help us ?
Yeah , I do .
COMMENTATOR [ ON RADIO ] : The count is 2-and-1 on the 74th pitch .
Away there , and a beautiful sinker right in the box .
Logonov swinging . Strike , to bring the count to 2-and-2 .
Now ...
[ STATIC OVER RADIO ]
And the windup .
Come on .
MAN [ ON RADIO ] : May God have mercy on your soul !
[ INDISTINCT WHISPERING ]
[ RADIO SHUTS OFF ]
[ INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE ]
EVELYN : Frankly , Mia ...
it 's none of your business .
This is between me and Leah ...
and she said she wanted those pajamas .
Heh . You are going to spoil her .
I haven 't had a chance for grandkids . And besides ,
- it 's impossible to spoil a baby . - Oh , I don 't know if that is true .
Well , we 'll certainly find out with Leah because ...
- she also pointed out these dresses . - Oh , Evelyn .
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
[ LEAH CRYING ]
[ MIA SHUSHING ]
Oh , sweetie pie , goodness gracious .
Oh , Mommy .
Okay . You know what , my Ruby used to fuss and fuss until I rocked her .
Put her down here .
She used to fuss and fuss . Come on .
Come here , honey . Alrighty . Okay . Here we go . Here we go , Leah .
[ MIA SHUSHING AND EVELYN SCATTING ]
EVELYN [ SINGING ] : We 're gonna rock that baby all night long
MIA : You are a lifesaver .
[ EVELYN CHUCKLING ]
What was it that you were humming ?
An old blues ditty .
It was the only thing that would settle my Ruby down when she was a baby .
Do you mind if I ask how she passed ? I don 't mind if ...
- If you don 't wanna talk about it , it 's fine . - No . No , it 's okay .
It was a car accident .
We were driving back from my parents ' .
They live up north .
So , uh , I was tired , you know .
Family will do that to you .
And it was very late and I shouldn 't have been behind the wheel .
Last thing I remember was ...
looking over in the passenger seat ...
at my daughter asleep .
Mia , she had grown into the most beautiful young woman .
I woke up three weeks later ...
and Ruby never did .
I didn 't get a chance to say goodbye .
I didn 't get to beg God to take me first .
I made the mistake ...
and she paid the price .
[ SIGHS ]
Father .
Where is it ?
- Where 's what ? - The doll .
You took it with you .
The evil .
Its presence .
I saw it , John .
I felt it .
I felt how much it wants .
Wants what ?
To take her soul .
But you said that it can 't take Leah 's . You said that it has to be offered .
Yes .
And a baby cannot offer its soul .
Oh , my God . Mia .
[ LEAH CRYING ]
[ PHONE RINGS ]
Here , I 'll get her .
- MIA [ OVER PHONE ] : Hello ? - Mia .
Father Perez was in an accident . He said ...
[ STATIC OVER PHONE ]
- MIA [ OVER PHONE ] : John ? - Mia , I need you to get out of the house .
... there . I am leaving now !
[ DIAL TONE ]
[ BANGING ON DOOR ]
MIA : Father Perez ?
Is everything all right ?
Father ?
May God have mercy on your soul !
EVELYN : Who is that ?
[ INDISTINCT CHANTING OVER PHONOGRAPH ]
We need to leave .
[ LEAH CRYING ]
MIA : Leah . Leah !
Leah !
Leah ! Leah !
Mia , the phone is dead . Come on .
- Oh , my God , it has my baby . - We 'll use the one in my apartment .
- You need to come with me . - No , I need to find Leah .
We 'll get her back . We need to get to church , they 'll help us . Come !
[ FOOTSTEPS THUDDING ]
[ GROWLING THEN MIA SCREAMING ]
Evelyn !
[ MIA SCREAMS ]
[ ROARING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ LEAH CRYING ]
Leah !
What do you want from me ?
[ LULLABY MUSIC PLAYING OVER MOBILE SPEAKER ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
You give her back to me !
You give her back ! Where is she ? !
[ GRUNTING ]
[ PANTING ]
Oh , God .
Leah !
[ CRYING ]
No !
No ! My baby !
Please , God , no !
Leah , Leah , Leah . Please , no .
[ DOLL GIGGLING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
Help ! Please !
Where is she ? !
There has to be another way !
MAN : Your soul .
Your soul .
[ SIGHS ]
[ LEAH CRYING ]
It 's okay .
Mommy 's coming to save you , Leah . Mommy 's coming .
Mia !
[ SOBBING ]
JOHN : Mia !
Mia !
Mommy 's coming .
- EVELYN : Mia ! - Hey !
- EVELYN : They 're in there , I can 't get in . - JOHN : Mia . Mia !
EVELYN : Mia !
JOHN : Mia , no !
Stop ! Stop !
Stop ! Stop . Stop .
JOHN : Okay , look , listen to me .
Please , come down .
It took my baby .
JOHN : Please , you gotta come down . Please come down . Okay ?
It wants her soul . I have to give it mine , John .
Mia , no ! Don 't do it .
It won 't give her back unless I ...
No , Mia , listen to me . Leah needs you here . Okay , sweetie ?
I need you here . Please , don 't do this .
I love you , John .
I love you .
I know you 'll take good care of our Leah .
You kiss her every night .
- When she 's older ... - Don 't . Please .
You tell her that I loved her .
No ! No !
- John , no ! - Stop . Stop .
- It wants her soul ! - Stop . You do not have to give in to it .
My baby !
- We can figure this out . - No !
Mia , listen to him .
You can 't do this to Leah .
A daughter needs her mother .
You said it needed a soul !
JOHN : Please ...
- MIA : Let me save her . - JOHN : Think about this .
Listen . You don 't wanna do this . Okay , listen to me . No , stop , stop .
You said you 'd save her . You said you 'd save her over me !
- You promised ! Please . - Think about our baby . Think about Leah .
Okay ? Think about her .
Please , don 't do this to us .
- It wants her soul . - There has to be another way .
EVELYN : There is .
I can make it right .
- Evelyn . - EVELYN : This is what Ruby meant .
- Evelyn . - JOHN : No , no !
[ MIA GASPS ]
[ MIA WHIMPERING ]
- I got you . - MIA : Evelyn .
[ MIA SOBBING ]
No . Evelyn .
[ LEAH WHIMPERS ]
Oh , my God .
FATHER PEREZ : God honors sacrifice .
And our sacrifices touch God 's heart and move his hand .
[ LEAH COOING ]
Jesus said , " This is my commandment .
That you love one another as I have loved you .
Greater love hath no one than this .
That he lay down his life for his friends . "
Let us pray .
[ CHURCH BELL TOLLING ]
JOHN : Wonderful sermon .
- MIA : You look well , Father . - FATHER PEREZ : Thank you , Mia .
And how are you doing ?
JOHN : We 're doing much better now . Thank you .
FATHER PEREZ : Has there been any sign of the doll ?
No , not since that night . I thought the police took it .
JOHN : But Detective Clarkin has no record of it .
But evil is constant . You cannot destroy what was never created .
I just pray that whomever comes into contact with the doll next
gets the help they need .
So do we .
- Good to see you . - The same .
- Bye , Father . - Goodbye , Mia .
Oh , I almost forgot .
MIA : Oh . It 's beautiful . Thank you , Father .
The loveliest masterpiece of the heart of God ...
is the love of a mother .
Thank you .
WOMAN 1 : Anything I can help you with ?
WOMAN 2 : Oh , I 'm just trying to find something for my daughter . Thanks .
She 's a nurse .
Always helping people .
We looked everywhere for one of these .
Never did find one .
WOMAN 1 : It 's a collector 's item , supposedly .
That 's why we price it a little higher than the rest .
- You want me to ring it up ? - WOMAN 2 : Yes , please .
[ LULLABY MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ CREAKING ]
[ English - US - SDH ]